# Sumit Dubey O Featured

Junior Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Unit Testing, Application Maintenance, Coding, database development, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, C, C++, Photoshop, React. Js, Python



Current Location: Mumbai Total Experience: 0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune, Navi Mumbai Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Junior Software Developer, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Unit Testing, Application Maintenance, Coding, database development, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, My

SQL,C,C++,Photoshop,React.Js,Python

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### Summary

A budding professional with extensive knowledge in Information Technology and Systems. Exposure to full project life cycle implementation with skills in software development. Exposure to end to end development of applications using diverse and latest technologies. An avid internet researcher with quest for knowledge pertaining to latest developments in the field of information technology and start up space.

Effective communicator and team player with strong interpersonal skills.

## **Work Experience**

**Biztran Solution Pvt. Ltd** as Junior Software Developer ASP.Net core Dec 2019 to Nov 2020

Planned and developed interfaces using PHP that simplified overall management and offered ease-of-use.

Collaborated on all stages of systems development lifecycle, from requirement

development lifecycle, from requiremen gathering to production releases.

Coordinated with project management staff on

database development timelines and project scope.

Gathered and defined customer requirements to

develop clear specifications for creating

well-organized project plans.

Expert in developing web-based applications and cross browser applications using .Net Framework.

Experience in patterns MVC,

Visual Studio various versions, Web services, XML and JSON

Hands on Experience in responsive front-end web designing using HTML5, CSS3, UI framework the Bootstrap v3 and v4 as well

**ACROSTIC IT SOLUTION PVT LTD** as Project Trainee -php and mysql Jun 2018 to Dec 2018

Project Details:- ERP application for SCM of a renowned paint manufacturer based in South India.

Project included maintenance and updation of data and all the SKUs manufactured and stock

Technologies used in the project:- Front End-Designed Front End module by using HTML 5,CSS3,Javascript,JQuery Back End- For Back End

we used PHP scripting language Database-Created database by using My SQL

Responsibilities:- Developed Front end and Back

end module of project.

Designed and managed Relational Databases.

Performed Troubleshoot to identify software performance issues.

Created development plans and project

documentation Technical Acumen: PHP, MySQL,

HTML-5, CSS-3, java script, jQuery, C, C.

Participated in creation and maintenance of

project tracking tools, verifying clear

communication of all inherent expectations and

responsibilities.

Tracked project financial metrics such as related

purchasing, invoice distribution and accounts receivable.

Maintained high levels of efficiency during training by taking detailed notes and asking questions.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Electronics Equipment Installation And Repair) from st.aloysius college jabalpur in 2008

PG: MCA (Computers) from Shri Ram Institute Of Technology - Jabalpur in 2019

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Web application development by using PHP and mySQL

Certificate in core python

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
HTML5		2019	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
CSS	3	2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JavaScript	JS ES6	2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JQUERY		2019	6 Month(s)
MySQL	10.1.38	2019	6 Month(s)
PHP	7.1.28	2019	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
ASP.Net MVC		0	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

# **Projects**

Project Title: ERP Application For SCM

Client: Reddy paints

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: ERP application for SCM of a renowned Paint manufacturer. Project included maintenance and updation of

data of all the SKUs manufactured and stock available

### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** Job Type: Permanent

Category: General

Employment Status: Full time